Austryn Wainhouse Papers
Austryn Wainhouse Papers
- Manuscripts
  - Miscellaneous, fragments, translations by others, etc.
    - Hecate: The adventure of Catherine Crochat, by Pierre Jean Jouve, translated by Lydia Davis, typescript with corrections (Box 16)
    - Notes and commentary: Barryism, by Matthew Mugg, 1952; published in Points 14; typescript carbon (Box 17)
    - Paris letter, by Matthew Mugg, typescript carbon (Box 17)
    - Reflexions upon the May festival and proposals for a spring offensive, by Hanssen Riley, 1952; published in Points 15; typescript carbon (Box 17)
    - Le wagon à vaches, by Georges Hyvernaud, translated by Dominic di Bernardi, typescript (Box 17)
- Memorabilia
  - Negatives (Box 23)
  - Photographs, circa 1930-2005; 5 folders (Box 23)
    The vast majority of these are candid shots of Wainhouse, friends, family, etc. Very few are labeled. Lacking dates and descriptions, no attempt has been made to organize these other than to group the obviously older photos together at the beginning. Subjects include Wainhouse himself at home and at events such as a book signing; friends and family; European travels; Vermont; etc. There is also a group of photographs of long wooden tables, possibly made by AW.
  - Scrapbook, newspaper clippings, Georgia currency (Oversize 1)
  - Slides, most are unlabeled; slides arrived completed disordered and no attempt has been made to organize them. (Oversize 2)
  - Slides, most are unlabeled; slides arrived completed disordered and no attempt has been made to organize them. (Oversize 3)
  - Wooden book cradle (Oversize 1)
  - Miscellaneous, membership cards, postcards, etc. (Box 23)
- Notebooks
  - Artra notes (Box 17)
    See also Manuscripts: Artra.
  - Chambord notebook, meeting with Bataille (Box 17)
  - Greek alphabet practice (Box 17)
  - Letter to a black countryman (Box 17)
  - Royal Calligraphe, only about 12 pp are used, rest is blank (Box 17)
  - Traveler from Peking (Box 17)
- Sade material
  - Original work
    - The Figure and doctrine of the Marquis de Sade, typescript carbon (Box 18)
    - Juliette Book III foreword, typescript with corrections (Box 18)
    - On the clandestine: Notes for an homage, typescript carbon with corrections (Box 18)
    - On translating Sade, 1966; typescript, galleys(?), printed version in Evergreen Review (Box 18)
    - Sade lecture, 1980; photcopy of handwritten manuscript (Box 18)
    - Translator's preface, photocopy of corrected typescript (Box 18)
  - Publicity
    - Grove, 1965-1967; advertisements, blurbs, etc. (Box 18)
    - Reviews, 1965-1967; undated; 3 folders (Box 18)
  - Translations, titles are given as written on covers
    - Juliette IIa, spiral notebook, handwritten (Box 18)
    - Juliette IIb, IIa, spiral notebook, handwritten (Box 18)
    - Juliette IIIb, spiral notebook, handwritten (Box 18)
    - Juliette IIIc, spiral notebook, handwritten (Box 18)
    - Juliette IIId, spiral notebook, handwritten (Box 19)
    - Juliette IIIe, IVa, spiral notebook, handwritten (Box 19)
    - Juliete IVb, spiral notebook, handwritten (Box 19)
    - Juliete IVc, spiral notebook, handwritten (Box 19)
    - Juliete vi-a, spiral notebook, handwritten (Box 19)
    - Juliette vi-b, spiral notebook, handwritten (Box 19)
    - Juliette vi-c, spiral notebook, handwritten (Box 19)
    - Juliette vi-d, spiral notebook, handwritten (Box 19)
    - Juliete VI (cont.), spiral notebook, handwritten (Box 19)
    - Letters from Vincennes and from the Bastille, Volume 1, typescript (Box 20)
    - Letters from Vincennes and from the Bastille, Volume 1, typescript carbon (Box 20)
    - Letters from Vincennes and from the Bastille, Volume 1, corrected keyboarded translation (Box 20)
    - Letters from Vincennes and from the Bastille, Volume 1 notebook 2, typescript (Box 20)
    - Letters from Vincennes and from the Bastille, Volume 1 notebook 2, handwritten; 2 folders (Box 20)
    - Letters from Vincennes and from the Bastille, Volume 1 notebook 2, photocopy of handwritten; 2 folders (Box 21)
    - Philosophia dans la boudoir, handwritten (Box 21)
    - Sade mon prochain, by Klossowski, 1952; first drafts (Box 21)
    - Short texts, Book I, several shorter pieces by Sade (Box 21)
    - Unidentified manuscript (Box 21)
  - Miscellaneous
    - Clippings, New York Times article on Sade; photocopy of two unidentified pages (Box 21)
    - "During his lifetime...", 2 paragraphs on Sade, author unknown; typescript carbon with corrections (Box 21)
    - Editor's foreword, no name, but presumably by Dick Seaver as editor (Box 21)
    - Kahane, "The Boudoir Philosophers", stage version of Philosophy in the Bedroom, by Eric Kahane (Box 21)
    - Klossowski preface, Volume II (Box 21)
    - Sade texts, AW's notes (Box 21)
- Miscellaneous
  - Photocopy of Paulina, by Pierre Jean Jouve (Box 21)
  - Photocopy of The Guiltless, by Hermann Broch (Box 22)
  - Printed material, 1955; 1967,; 1982,; 1995,; 1998-1999,; 2006; clippings, prinouts of articles, issue of The Nation from June of 1967 (Box 22)